<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='./_c74_ref.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>
<c74object name="ibufconcatedrive~" module="AHarker Externals" category="ibuffer suite">
  <digest>
      Drive unit for concatenated buffer
  </digest>
  <description>
      The <o>ibufconcatedrive~</o> object is high resolution drive object (accumulator) that is internally clipped according to the given items (or chunks) associated with a buffer (items are stored using the <o>ibufconcatenate~</o> object). Typically this object forms part of a sample-accurate sampler or granulator, and is used in conjunction with <o>play~</o> (or historically <o>hr.play~</o>). By use of this system (first concatentating samples, then referencing them in this way) it is possible to cleanly and accurately switch between the contents of the source buffers in a sample-accurate manner. The speed input controls playback speed. The item input selects the item from those associated with the buffer (0 is no item / -1 is the whole buffer). When the reset trigger is non-zero the item input will be read, and the output will be set to the value specified at the reset value inlet (this should be given as the actual position into the <o>buffer~</o> in ms, rather than relative to the item).
  </description>
  
  <objarglist>
      <objarg name="(i)buffer_name" optional="0" type="symbol">
          <digest>
              Set the (i)buffer~ name
          </digest>
          <description>
              The first argument is the <o>ibuffer~</o> /<o>buffer~</o> to attach to and ouput position data from.
          </description>
      </objarg>
      <objarg name="initial_value" optional="1" type="float">
          <digest>
              Set the initial value
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set the initial playback position.
              <br />
              Default is <m>0</m>
          </description>
      </objarg>
  </objarglist>

  <methodlist>
      <method name="signal">
          <arglist>
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Function depends on inlet
          </digest>
          <description>
              In the first inlet: Set the playback speed multiplier.
              <br/>
              <br/>
              In the second inlet: Set the item stored in <o>ibufconcatenate~</o> to play.
              <br/>
              <br/>
              In the third inlet: Set the start position in milliseconds to begin playback from when a reset trigger is received in the fourth inlet.
              <br/>
              <br/>
              In the fourth inlet: A tigger <m>signal</m> will reset the playback position to the position set by the third inlet.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="set">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="set" type="symbol" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Set the (i)buffer to attach to
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set the <o>ibuffer~</o> /<o>buffer~</o> to attach to and ouput position data from.
          </description>
      </method>
  </methodlist>
  
  <attributelist>
  </attributelist>
  <misc name="Output">
    <entry name="signal">
        <description>
           The first outlet outputs the playback position as a <m>signal</m> for use in <o>play</o>.
           <br />
           The second outlet outputs hi-res position to work with <o>hr.play~</o>.
        </description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
  <seealsolist>
    <seealso name="ibuftable~" />
    <seealso name="ibufconcatenate~" />
    <seealso name="ibuffermulti~" />
    <seealso name="ibufinfo~" />
    <seealso name="ibufmultitable~" />
    <seealso name="ibufplayer~" />
    <seealso name="ibuffer~" />
    <seealso name="buffer~" />
    <seealso name="play~" />
  </seealsolist>
  <misc name="Discussion">
    <entry name="Keywords">
      <description>ibuffer suite</description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
</c74object>
