<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='./_c74_ref.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>
<c74object name="randfloats" module="AHarker Externals" category="Random Numbers">
  <digest>
      High quality random float values
  </digest>
  <description>
    <o>randfloats</o> is an object for generating high quality random numbers (either 0-1 or 0-n) using either flat or windowed gaussian distributions. Three gaussian functions may also be used simultaneously to create a more complex distribution, with weighting values used to randomly determine which is used.
  </description>
  
  <methodlist>
      <method name="bang">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="first-inlet" optional="1" type="bang" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Output a linearly distributed <m>float</m>
        </digest>
        <description>
            A <m>bang</m> to the first-inlet will cause an output of a linearly distributed <m>float</m> between 0. and 1.
        </description>
      </method>
      <method name="bang">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="second-inlet" optional="1" type="bang" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Output a windowed gaussian distribution
        </digest>
        <description>
            A <m>bang</m> to the second-inlet will cause a <m>float</m> output between 0. and 1. of a windowed gaussian distribution. The parameters for the distribution can be set by sending the <m>mean</m> and <m>deviation</m> as a single message in the left-inlet.
        </description>
      </method>
      <method name="bang">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="third-inlet" optional="1" type="bang" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Output a triple windowed gaussian distribution
        </digest>
        <description>
            A <m>bang</m> to the third-inlet will cause a <m>float</m> output between 0. and 1. of a triple windowed gaussian distribution. The parameters for the distribution can be set by sending three sets of:
            <br />
            <br />
            <m>mean</m> / <m>deviation</m> / <m>weight</m>
            <br />
            <br />
            as a single message in the left-inlet.
        </description>
      </method>
      <method name="message">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="windowed gaussian distribution" optional="1" type="message" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Set the parameters for the windowed gaussian distribution
        </digest>
        <description>
            A <m>message</m> to the left-inlet formatted as:
            <br />
            <br />
            <m>mean</m> / <m>deviation</m>
            <br />
            <br />
            will set the parameters for the windowed gaussian distribution for when a <m>bang</m> is sent the the second-inlet.
        </description>
      </method>
      <method name="message">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="triple windowed gaussian distribution" optional="1" type="message" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Set the parameters for the triple windowed gaussian distribution
        </digest>
        <description>
            A <m>message</m> to the left-inlet formatted as three sets of:
            <br />
            <br />
            <m>mean</m> / <m>deviation</m> / <m>weight</m>
            <br />
            <br />
            will set the parameters for the triple windowed gaussian distribution for when a <m>bang</m> is sent the the third-inlet.
        </description>
      </method>
      <method name="int">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="multiplier" optional="1" type="int" />
          </arglist>
        <digest>
            Set a multiplier for the output
        </digest>
        <description>
            Sending an <m>int</m> (n) into any inlet of <o>randfloats</o> will cause its ouput to be multiplied by that value, changing the output range into 0 to n.
        </description>
      </method>
  </methodlist>
  
  <attributelist>
  </attributelist>
  <misc name="Output">
    <entry name="float">
        <description>
            Outputs a high quality random <m>float</m> in the range of either 0. to 1. or 0 to n.
        </description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
  <seealsolist>
    <seealso name="ahnoise~" />
    <seealso name="randomvals" />
    <seealso name="randomvals~" />
  </seealsolist>
  <misc name="Discussion">
    <entry name="Keywords">
      <description>random numbers</description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
</c74object>
