<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='./_c74_ref.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>
<c74object name="timefilter" module="AHarker Externals" category="Gesture_Suite">
  <digest>
      Filter a list to remove values that are too close together
  </digest>
  <description>
      Originally intended for use with lists representing time values as part of a system of gestural representation, <o>timefilter</o> is an object for filtering and reordering values in a list of numbers. The stored list is first sorted (if desired) either into ascending order or randomly. Values may then either be filtered randomly, or according to a minimum required distance between values (originally to avoid events timed too closely together), or a combination of the two. The object may obviously be used on lists representing any parameter and in various other scenarios than the one from which it takes its name.
  </description>
  <methodlist>
      <method name="bang">
          <arglist>
          </arglist>
          <digest>
               Output and clear the list
          </digest>
          <description>
              Output the <m>list</m> after sorting and filtering. Then clear to prepare for the next input.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="float">
          <arglist>
          </arglist>
          <digest>
               Set distance between list items
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set a <m>float</m> to determine the minimum distance between items in the <m>list</m>. Items that do no satisfy this limit are filtered out.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="list">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="input" type="list" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Set the list to be filtered
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set the <m>list</m> to be reordered and filtered when <o>timefilter</o> recieves a bang.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="ordering">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="ordering" type="int" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Set the ordering mode of the list
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set the ordering mode for the <m>list</m> processing. This determines the order before filtering is applied.
              <br />
              <br />
              <m>ordering 0</m> - sort in ascending order
              <br />
              <m>ordering 1</m> - random sort
              <br />
              <m>ordering 2</m> - maintain input ordering
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="randfilter">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="randfilter" type="float" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Randomly filter the list
          </digest>
          <description>
              Set a ratio by which to randomly filter the <m>list</m>.
              <br />
              The message should be formatted as:
              <br />
              <br />
              <m>randfilter</m> / <m>float</m> (0-1)
              <br />
              <br />
              Ex. <m>randfilter 0.2</m> will randomly filter out 20% of items.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="reset">
          <arglist>
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Clear the input list
          </digest>
          <description>
              Clear the input <m>list</m> without outputting.
          </description>
      </method>
  </methodlist>
  <attributelist>
  </attributelist>
  <misc name="Output">
    <entry name="list">
        <description>
            Outputs the input <m>list</m> as <m>floats</m> after being ordered then filtered.
        </description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
  <seealsolist>
    <seealso name="gesture_maker" />
    <seealso name="timemap" />
  </seealsolist>
  <misc name="Discussion">
    <entry name="Keywords">
      <description>Gesture_Suite</description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
</c74object>
