<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' standalone='yes'?>
<?xml-stylesheet href='./_c74_ref.xsl' type='text/xsl'?>
<c74object name="voicedrive~" module="AHarker Externals" category="sample accurate suite">
  <digest>
      Sample-accurate ramp / grain / timing object
  </digest>
  <description>
      <o>voicedrive~</o> is a (sub)sample-accurate (usually non-interrupting) ramp generator with several useful outputs for driving grains, playback voices or other similar processes. Typically <o>voicedrive~</o> is used in connection with the <o>voicemanager~</o> object, as the drive unit for each individual voice of a process. Because <o>voicedrive~</o> is a non-interrupting (in default mode) it can also be used for other sample-accurate timing purposes such as random length ramping (for interpolation between values for example).
  </description>
  <objarglist>
      <objarg name="hi-res" optional="1" type="int">
          <digest>
              Turn on Hi-res
          </digest>
          <description>
              hi-res position mode flag (if on outputs position in hi-res for use with jkc's hr objects or similar).
          </description>
      </objarg>
      <objarg name="allow-interrupt" optional="1" type="int">
          <digest>
              Allow interrupts
          </digest>
          <description>
              Allow interrupts flag (normally you cannot interrupt a ramp / grain that is executing. If this flag is on triggers always start a new ramp).
          </description>
      </objarg>
  </objarglist>

  <methodlist>
      <method name="First-inlet">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="First-inlet" type="signal" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Triggers in
          </digest>
          <description>
              The first inlet takes a trigger <m>signal</m> used to begin the ramp outputs.
              <br />
              When not in <m>mode 2</m>, consecutive triggers will be ignored until the busy flag is lowered.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="Second-inlet">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="Second-inlet" type="signal" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Lengths in
          </digest>
          <description>
              The second inlet takes a <m>signal</m> to determine the length (in milliseconds) of the ramp outputs.
              <br />
              This will effect the duration of the ramps, as well as the values of the ramp coming from the first outlet.
              <br />
              The input value is sampled when a trigger is recieved in the first inlet.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="Third-inlet">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="Third-inlet" type="signal" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Subsample offset
          </digest>
          <description>
              The subsample offset is for many applications not necessary. However, if for some reason you need better than sample-accurate timing (for pitched prcoesses et.) you can utilise this functionality.
              <br />
              <br />
              It works by pre-advancing the ramps by the given subsample offset (between 0 and 1). The logic behind this is that for detection process, detection can only happen after the event (in this case crossing the 0 or 1 point) has taken place. Thus, the trigger occurs late by a fraction of a sample. To compensate for this, we advance the ramps by that amount to acheive subsample accuracy. Offset is applied to both the normalised and position ramps of <o>voicedrive~</o> and <o>voicemanager~</o> also takes account of the subsample offset.
          </description>
      </method>
      <method name="Fourth-inlet">
          <arglist>
              <arg name="Fourth-inlet" type="signal" />
          </arglist>
          <digest>
              Offsets in
          </digest>
          <description>
              The fourth inlet takes a <m>signal</m> to determine the offset (start value) in milliseconds of the ramp being output from the first outlet.
              <br />
              The input value is sampled when a trigger is recieved in the first inlet.
          </description>
      </method>
  </methodlist>
  <attributelist>
  </attributelist>
  <misc name="Output">
    <entry name="signal">
        <description>
            The first outlet outputs a linear ramp <m>signal</m> to indicate a playback position in milliseconds.
            <br />
            The second outlet outputs a normalised ramp <m>signal</m> (0-1).
            <br />
            The third outlet outputs a <m>signal</m> trigger at the beginning of each ramp.
            <br />
            The fourth outlet outputs the busy flag.
        </description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
  <seealsolist>
    <seealso name="chebyshape~" />
    <seealso name="rbiquad~" />
    <seealso name="rdcblock~" />
    <seealso name="triggerlimit~" />
    <seealso name="rsah~" />
    <seealso name="voicemanager~" />
  </seealsolist>
  <misc name="Discussion">
    <entry name="Keywords">
      <description>sample accurate suite</description>
    </entry>
  </misc>
</c74object>
